Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
The Night Before the Second Exam
あっ。
(カンクロウ)どこへ行くつもりだ？
Where are you trying to go?
この奥は風影の部屋だが。
The Kazekage's quarters
are beyond here.
(カンクロウ)待ちやがれ！
Hold it!
貴様 何者だ！
Who the hell are you?!
我は 風の国を正す者。
We seek to reform the Land of Wind!
逃がすか！
You think I'd let you get away?!
もう逃げ道はねえじゃん。
You have nowhere to run...
クッ。
天誅！
Divine Punishment!
(テマリ)伏せて！
Take cover!
ふっ 戻ってたのか。
Oh, you're back.
(テマリ)まったく…
油断してんじゃないよ。
Damn it...
Be more careful.
(我愛羅)改まって 話とは何だ？
You wanted to talk to me?
(カンクロウ)頼む 我愛羅➡
Please, Gaara, forget about
supervising the Chunin Exams.
今度の中忍試験の監督官は
やめてくれ。
お前を狙う連中の動きが
活発になってる。
The people targeting you
are stepping up their efforts.
そこにノコノコ出ていったら
思うつぼだ。
You'll just be playing into
their hands if you continue this!
(我愛羅)
そんなことはわかっている。
I already know that.
だが それで俺がやめたら➡
But if I quit because of that,
やつらに屈したと
宣言するようなものだ。
it would be like declaring that
I will cave in under pressure.
そうかもしれないが
たかが中忍試験じゃん。
Maybe so, but...
But this is only the Chunin Exams!
(我愛羅)中忍試験は
俺の すべての始まり。
The Chunin Exams is where
everything began for me.
俺は あいつのおかげで
ここまで来られた。
Thanks to him,
I've made it this far.
今回の中忍試験➡
I'll make sure these Chunin Exams
are a success...
必ず成功させてみせる。
... without fail.
(シビレ)やっと着いた 砂隠れ。
We've finally reached
Hidden Sand territory.
よし 二次試験会場に…。
All right, let's go to
the second-round site.
猿飛先生に 夕日先生。
Sarutobi Sensei! Yuhi Sensei!
(紅)残念だけど
キミたちはここまでよ。
Sorry, but this is as far as you'll go.
(アスマ)到着が遅れた受験生は
足切りだ。
Late arrivals are disqualified.
木ノ葉の受験生は里に戻れ。
If you're from the Hidden Leaf,
return to the village.
他の里の者たちも ここで解散だ。
The rest of you can disperse
from here too.
(シビレ)そんな…
３日も走り続けてきたのに。
But we ran nonstop for
three days to get here!
あなたたち
ここで愚痴が出るようなら➡
If you're complaining,
失格になって
よかったかもしれないわね。
then maybe it's for the best
that you're being eliminated.
えっ。
何しろ ここから先は➡
That's because hell is beyond this point.
生きて戻れるかわからない
地獄だからな。
And who knows if you'll even
get out of there alive.
(リー)あっ サクラさん 皆さん
無事に着きましたね。
Sakura! Everyone!
You made it!
(サクラ)さすがガイ先生のとこは
体力あるわね。
I must admit,
Guy Sensei's team sure has stamina.
(ネジ)アスマ班… 紅班➡
Team Asuma, Team Kurenai...
前回の主要メンバーは
足切りに合わなかったようだな。
The main members from
that last time made it through.
(ガイ)うむ みんな よく頑張った。
Yup! You all gave it your all!
三日三晩 寝る間も惜しみ➡
The fortitude you showed in running for
three days and three nights without sleep
走りとおしたキミたちの努力に
今 先生は心から感動してる！
has made me so proud!
思い返せば
先生も中忍試験の頃…。
Why, it takes me back to the time
I took the Chunin Exams...
(キバ)先生 その話長いなら…。
Sensei... If you're going to
tell us a long story...
(チョウジ)早く休ませてください。
腹ぺこです。
Please let us rest already.
I'm starving.
ん… だな。
Seems like it.
(リー)砂隠れって初めて来ましたが。
We've never been to
the Hidden Sand before...
(テンテン)ほんとに
砂漠しかないとこね。
It really is nothing but desert.
正確には
ここは砂隠れの里じゃない。
To be accurate,
this really isn't Hidden Sand Village.
ここは ずいぶんと
里から離れている。
It's quite far from the village.
ネジは 砂隠れに
行ったことがあるんですか？
Neji, have you ever been to
the Hidden Sand Village?
一度 日向家の使いでな。
Once on an errand for the Hyuga.
ここは魔の砂漠の監視所だ。
This is the Demon Desert checkpoint.
(テンテン)なるほどね。
そこを使ってるのか。
I see.
So this is what they're using.
何か 他の里で受験する
っていうのは緊張しますね。
Taking the Exams in a different village
is sort of nerve-wracking.
二次試験の内容は
どんなものになるんでしょう。
I wonder what
the second round will be like.
きっと前回と
似たようなもんじゃないの？
It's probably like
last time.
じゃあ 次は他里との戦いですね。
So we'll be battling teams
from other villages?
可能性は高いな。
だとしたら➡
There's a good chance of that.
Then we'll have to be wary
of some teams.
用心しなきゃいけない
班がありますね。
僕たちは ずいぶんと飛ばしたのに
一着になれなかった。
We went at full-speed,
yet we weren't the first to arrive.
一着は 滝隠れよね。
The Hidden Waterfall were
the first to arrive.
しかも俺たちより
ずいぶんと先に到着したようだ。
Not only that,
they got here long before us.
いったい
どんな相手なんでしょう。
Just what kind of opponents
are they?
(フウ)開けるっす！
どうなってるっす？
C'mon, open up!
What's going on?
The door won't open!
扉が開かないっす！
(トッチ)すまないがフウ キミには
あすの朝までそこにいてもらう。
Sorry, Fuu.
Stay in there until morning.
(フウ)えっ？ どうしてっすか？
Huh?! Why's that?
(クン)キミの行動は どうも読めない。
We never know what you'll do next.
頼むから二次試験のために
我々を少し休ませてくれ。
So please, give us a break and
let us rest up for the next round.
(フウ)えっ!? そんな。
それじゃ みんなと遊べないっす。
Huh? Hey!
That means I can't go and
have fun with the others!
だから その心がけがまずいのだ！
See, that's what worries us.
[スピーカ]夕食の用意ができました。
受験者は食堂に来てください。
Dinner is ready.
Entrants, please assemble
in the cafeteria.
(サクラ)あれが砂隠れ。
So that's Hidden Sand Village...
(キバ)砂隠れの連中
堂々とメンチ切りやがって。
check out the Hidden Sand...
giving everyone the stink eye.
目つき悪すぎだぜ。
They sure look mean.
って キバ。
あんたの目つきも相当悪いわよ。
Well, Kiba... You look pretty mean too.
(いの)そして あっちが雨隠れで➡
And over there
are the Hidden Rain.
どうやらあっちが草隠れみたいね。
I guess the other side
is the Hidden Grass.
(チョウジ)すごいよ あの人。
That guy's amazing.
ほんとですね。
ぽっちゃり系のチョウジ君が➡
I'll say.
Compared to him, even
our slightly chubby Choji looks normal.
普通の人に見えます。
(いの)でもあの汗…
マジ ドン引きなんだけど。
But the way he sweats...
Seriously, that's gross.
(テンテン)ねえ ちょっと
やな予感がするんだけど。
Hey...
I'm getting a bad feeling...
うん？ やな予感？
Bad feeling?
あれだけの汗…
もしあの人が料理に近づけば…。
All that sweat.
If he gets close to the food...
あぁっ！
(ブラミ)
さて 晩飯 食べ始めようかな。
All right! Time to eat dinner!
う～っ。
ひぃっ！
うぅ…。
このままじゃ…。
俺たちの晩飯は…。
At this rate...
Our dinner will be...
(みんな)うわぁ～っ！
だ… ギャ～！
(キバ)しまった！
Damn!
キャ～！
八卦掌 回天！
Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
た 助かった。
S-Saved...
Uh... I do not think so.
いえ 助かってないみたいですよ。
(ミコシ)キミたち 僕らの夕食を！
What did you do to our dinner?
(ユカタ)どういうつもりなの？
What are you thinking?
(カザミ)お前ら 俺たちの仲間を！
What did you do to our friend?!
(リー)誤解です！ 僕たちは➡
Don't misunderstand!
We wanted to protect our food!
自分のご飯を守るために
やったんですから！
自分たちの分だけ確保して
あとはダメにする作戦だった➡
So you were going to save your food
and never mind the rest of us, right?
そうでしょ？
何言ってやがる！
What're you saying?!
俺たちが そんな姑息な真似
するか！
We'd never stoop to
something like that!
(キバ)そんなこと疑うなんて
我愛羅のしつけがなってねえな！
Your suspicion shows that
Gaara hasn't trained you right!
(マツリ)あんた 今
我愛羅様の悪口 言ったね。
Did you just criticize Lord Gaara?
絶対… 許さないからね！
That is absolutely unforgivable!
この野郎！
やめてください！
皆さん やめてください！
Stop!
Please stop, everyone!
ちょっと！ やめなさいよ！
Hey, stop it!
(テンテン)ネジ 止めないの？
Neji! Aren't you going to stop them?
悪いが 今は忙しい。
Sorry, but I'm busy right now.
Burami!
ブラミ 落ちたもん
食ってんじゃねえよ！
Don't eat food off the ground!
ムヤミ お前も手伝え！
Muyami! You help too!
(ムヤミ)いい 僕 人見知りだから。
I'll pass... I'm too shy.
皆さん 落ち着い…
ケンカはいけま…。
Calm down, every—!
Do not fight—!
Why you...!
てめえ！
うぉ… いい加減に 言うことを
聞いてください！ だ～っ！
Will you stop... and listen to me?!
(シラ)こんな狭いところで
その技は大げさすぎる。
This room is way too small for
a flashy move like that.
《手を抜いたとはいえ
僕の技を片手で…》
I didn't do that at full strength,
but still...
To be able
to stop me with one hand...
(キバ)な 何の音だ!?
What's that sound?
フウ！
(２人)あっ！
Fuu!
(フウ)ジャジャジャ ジャ～ン！
Ta-dah!
(フウ)おう もうパーティーは
始まってたっすね。
So the party's already started, guys?!
みんな 100人の友ができるかな？
I wonder if I can make a hundred friends?
だ 誰？
Wh-Who are you?
滝隠れから来た フウっす。
I'm Fuu from the Village Hidden
in the Waterfall!
《ネジ : こいつ…》
This one...
あっし 100人の友を作るために
中忍試験を受けに来たっす。
I came to the Chunin Exams
to make a hundred friends!
みんな 食事のあとは何する？
So guys, what's the plan
after dinner?
(フウ)トランプ？ すごろく？
イスとりゲーム？
Cards? Backgammon? Musical chairs?
それとも… み～んな一緒に
風呂でも入っちゃう？
Or...
How about we all take
a bath together?
(キバ)何だ？ お前。
What's with you?
(みんな)ハァ～…。
これで 晩ご飯抜きか…。
Oh well, so much for dinner...
(チョウジ)もう帰る。
えっ あれ？
I'm going back.
Huh? Hey...
ちょ～ ちょちょちょ！
W-Wait!
Don't go!
ちょっと待ってよ！
みんな あっしと遊ぼうよ！
Hey guys, play with me!
(ネジ)しかし この騒動を
あんなバカで止めてしまうとは➡
Well...
It took an idiot like that
to stop the ruckus...
まるで 誰かを思い出す。
ナルトね。
Sort of reminds me of someone.
I know... Naruto.
まったくよね リー。
Right, Lee?
あれ？ リー。
(リー)あのう 待ってください。
Huh? Lee?
Excuse me, please wait!
さっき触れたとき わかりました。
I realized it when
I made contact earlier.
キミは 他の人とは違う。
You are not like the others.
キミは 僕の技を軽々と受け止めた。
You stopped my attack
with such ease.
自分で言うのも何なんですけど➡
It may sound arrogant
coming from me,
あんなこと
並大抵の人には絶対できません。
but it takes someone
extraordinary to do that.
だから わかるんです➡
That's why I can tell...
あなたも
すごい努力をしてきた人だって。
That you have had to overcome
great odds like me.
何が言いたい？
What are you trying to say?
つまり キミは僕と同じ。
Well... that you and I are alike.
キミのことは知っている。
I know about you.
木ノ葉のロック・リー。
You're Rock Lee of the Hidden Leaf.
俺は 砂隠れのシラだ。
I'm Shira of the Hidden Sand.
シラ君。
Shira...
お前が何を感じたかは知らない。
I don't know what it is you sensed,
だが 生まれの不幸を
嘆いても意味などない。
but dwelling on the misfortunes
of birth is meaningless.
その不幸を含めて
人生はひとつしかないからな。
Because, for all of one's flaws
and suffering,
we have just one life.
人生の真実は
俺にとって ただひとつ。
To me, there is only one truth in life.
人生の真実…。
One truth in life?
努力は 人を裏切らない。
Determination never betrays you.
シラ君…。
Shira...
(カカシ)綱手様 ただ今戻りました。
Lady Tsunade, I've returned.
(綱手)ご苦労だった。
それで首尾は？
I'm glad you made it back.
So how did it go?
(カカシ)報告したように
半蔵には 直接会えませんでした。
As I reported, I wasn't able
to see Hanzo in person.
(カカシ)密かに里に戻り
内情を探ろうと思ったのですが。
I intended to sneak back in and
investigate, but...
((この辺りに侵入者がいるはずだ
捜せ！
The infiltrator must be around here!
Find him!
(何!? もう感知されただと!?))
What?
They've discovered
my presence already?
(カカシ)こちらの動きが
筒抜けのようでした。
They were on to me from the start.
あれは まるで➡
It was almost as though...
死人の視線。
ghosts were watching me.
Well...
しかし…。
I was expecting just
the usual Chunin Exams,
たかが 中忍試験と思っていたが➡
いざ始めてみれば 各里の➡
But now that it's started,
we're discovering some
interesting things about each village.
いろいろと おもしろいことが
わかってきたな。
おもしろいこと？
Interesting things?
(チョウジ)はぁ。
(いの)チョウジ。
Choji...
何やってんの？
What are you doing?
Ino...
いの ねえ あの建物は？
(いの)ん？
What's that building?
あっ 先生たちの宿舎ね。
Oh, that's where the Senseis
are staying.
先生の!?
The Senseis?!
(サクラ)あっ？ ちょっとチョウジ？
Hey, Choji!
(チョウジ)あそこに行けば
きっとご飯を分けてもらえるよ。
I'll bet they'll give us some food
if we go there!
夜はうろつくなって
言われてるでしょ？
We're not supposed to
wander around at night!
腹ぺこで正常な判断力を
失ってるわね。
He's so hungry,
he can't think straight!
連れ戻すわよ。
Let's go after him!
ヌフハハハハハ ハハ。
(チョウジ)ハハハハ！
Choji! Where are you?!
チョウジ どこ？
(チョウジ)ぬわ～！
– Choji?!
(２人)チョウジ。
は～ 友達。
Friends...
(チョウジ)ぬあ～！
えっ？
白眼。
Byakugan!
何だ この影は。
What is that shadow?
(アメノ)今の声は？ まさか。
Whose voice was that?!
No way...
(アメノ)誰か外に出たんですか？
Did someone go outside?
(フウ)何すか？ あっ！
What?
Oh! Cards? Backgammon?!
トランプ？ すごろく！
この季節は夜になると➡
Giant scorpions come out at night
during this time of year!
巨大なサソリが出るんです。
だから 外に出るなって。
That's why you were told
not to go outside!
そんなやつが いるんすか！
You have things like that?!
あっ ちょっと。
Hey!
うわ～！
(いの)チョウジ 今 助けるから。
Choji!
I'm here to help you!
うわっ 何これ？
What is this thing?!
ぬあ～！
Hidden Waterfall Hurricane!
滝隠れの旋風！
うあ～！
うわ～！
フ～ やっふ～！
Yahoo! This is fun!
おもしろい！
No! Stop!
うわっ くっ やめて。
うぅ 何なの？
W-What's happening?!
ちょっと 遊んでないで
倒しなさいよ。
Hey!
Stop fooling around,
and take that thing down!
Huh? It's over already...?!
え～ もう終わり？
(サクラ)危ないじゃない
うっ うわ～！
It's dangerous!
もう しようがないっすね。
Aww... Guess I have no choice!
ギュオ～！
サクラさん 大丈夫ですか？
Sakura, are you all right?
(サクラ)ええ。
Yeah...
(リー)あ～ でも血が出てます。
But you're bleeding!
(サクラ)大丈夫だから。
I'm okay.
(アメノ)動かないでください。
Please don't move.
《この子➡
This girl...
私と同じ医療忍者？》
She's a Medical Ninja like me...
(アメノ)これで大丈夫です。
ありがとう。
That should do it.
Thank you.
《サクラ : いい腕してる》
She's got skill.
やっほ～ やっほ～！
Yahoo!
Yahoo yahoo-hoo!
やっほほいのほ～い！
Jeez...
まったく。
世話が焼ける。
What a pain...
《また あいつか。
Her again...
どうやって いち早く駆けつけた？
How'd she show up so fast?
しかし あっという間に
こんな化けものを倒すとは》
And she brought down
that monster in no time.
(ガイ)なっ 何だこれは！
W-What is this?!
いったい何の騒ぎだ。
What's going on?
(テマリ)夜の外出は禁止のはず。
Going outside at night is prohibited.
(テマリ)二次試験は
夜明け前に開始だ。
The Second Exam begins
before dawn breaks!
早く宿舎に戻れ。
Hurry up and return
to your quarters!
すみません。
ガイ先生。
– We're sorry.
– Guy Sensei!
W-We're starving!
おっ お腹が空いてるんです。
えっ!? まったくお前たちは。
You guys are...
とっとと戻らんか！
Go back now!
心頭滅却すれば 火もまた涼し。
Clear your mind of mundane thoughts
and even a fire will go out!
あぁ。
人は１食抜いたくらいでは
死なん！
Missing one meal won't kill a person!
修業の一環だと思え！
Just think of this
as part of training!
あぁ。
(フウ)えっ えっ え～！
Huh? Huh?
Huh?! You're all leaving?
もうみんな帰っちゃうの？
がっくしっす。
I'm so sad...
(我愛羅)お前はお人よしだな。
You're a good person....
To help foes from other villages.
敵である 他里の者を助けるとは。
放っておけば
ライバルが減ったものを。
If you had ignored them, you would've
ended up with fewer rivals.
だって あっしには敵とか➡
I don't care about rivals or allies.
味方とか関係ないし。
♪♪「100人の友が出来るかな」
I wonder if I'm going to make
a hundred friends!
そうだ キミたち
あっしと友達にならない？
Hey, let's be friends!
Wanna play cards? Backgammon?
トランプ？ すごろく？
(２人)あっ。
(フウ)それとも➡
Or... wanna bathe together?!
一緒にお風呂に入る？
(クン)あの方たちは 風影様と➡
They are the Lord Kazekage
and the jonin supervisors!
監督官の上忍様たちだぞ。
どんな口きいてるんだ!?
Watch what you say!
One hundred...!
100人！
友達。
(トッチ)いいから戻るぞ。
– Enough! Let's go back!
– ...friends!
(我愛羅)敵も味方も関係ないか。
Doesn't care about rivals or allies, huh.
どこか似ているのかもしれんな。
Sounds just like someone I know.
Gaara?
(テマリ)我愛羅？
いや。
It's nothing.
(我愛羅)楽しみが増えた。
Now I have more to look forward to
in the Chunin Exams.
今回の中忍試験。
少しは おもしろそうな連中が
参加している。
Thanks to a few interesting
characters taking part in it.
(テマリ)では これより
中忍二次試験の説明をする。
All right...
I'm going to explain the second round
of the Chunin Exams.
The Second Exam will be
a competition for scrolls
二次試験は 魔の砂漠での
巻物争奪戦をやってもらう。
to be held in the Demon Desert.
つまり 究極のサバイバル・バトルだ。
In other words,
this is the ultimate survival battle!
巻物には
天の書と地の書の２つがある。
There are two scrolls,
Heaven and Earth.
EARTH    HEAVEN
半分のチームには 天の書を。
Half the teams will be
given Heaven scrolls.
もう半分のチームには 地の書を渡す。
The other half will get Earth scrolls.
この試験の合格条件は➡
The objective of this exam
is to obtain both the Heaven
and Earth scrolls
天と地 両方の書を持って➡
魔の砂漠の中央にある
拠点まで行くこと。
and to bring them back
to the base
located in the center
of the Demon Desert.
期限は 72時間。
You have 72 hours.
Find food on your own!
食料は自給自足だ。
ここから先は 死人も出る。
Starting now,
there may be fatalities.
Every participating team member
will sign a consent form!
参加チームのメンバーは全員➡
同意書にサインしろ。
When you turn in the team
consent forms, you will be given a scroll!
CONSENT FORM
メンバー全員の同意書と
巻物を交換する。
Furthermore, to avoid confusion,
なお 開始早々の
混乱を避けるため➡
each team will start from
a different location.
各チームは 別々の場所からスタートする。
各チーム 速やかに
スタート地点へ向かえ。
So be quick,
and go to your starting points!
(リー)ついに始まりましたね。
It's finally starting...
The second round
of the Chunin Exams!
第二次中忍試験。
We don't know what lies ahead.
(ネジ)どんなことが
待ち受けているか わからない。
So let's stay on our toes.
気を引き締めて行くぞ。
– Right!
– Okay!
(リー)はい。
(テンテン)うん。
nando tatakitsukerarete mo
No matter how many times I get beat down
akiramerareru wake nado wanaku genten kaiki
I can't give up, so I go back to my basics
genjitsu to wa baibai shite
I wish we could say bye-bye to this reality
mukashi mitai ni waiwai shitai keredo
And have fun like we used to
sou mo ikanai nara kirihiraite mirya ii
But it doesn't work that way,
so let's carve out our own paths
nokori wazuka no shouki torimodoshite
I'll make you get back the little sanity you have left
me no mae no tobira kojiakete miseru
And then tear down the door in front of you
itsudemo sou nanda
That's the way it is
wasuregachina koto ga
The things you tend to forget
nani yori mo taisetsuna koto datte
Are the things that are the most important
nani ga machiukete iyou to kamawanai
I don't care what lies ahead
ame nimo makezu yami o terasu
The rain won't stop me from lighting up the darkness
kono kyoujin na kokoro ga areba
As long as I have this strong spirit
kono toki kono basho ni tsudoishi nakamatachi
Friends who gather at this time, at this place
mawari tsudzukeru sekai nanbitotari
The world keeps spinning, No one can stop it
tomo tomeru koto wa dekinai yo
Our priority is to find
the other scroll.
レディース アンド ジェントルマン。
今宵
嫌なこと忘れて楽しみましょ。
To do that, we're going to have
to fight another team for it.
We were fortunate that brawl happened
in the cafeteria last night.
イッツ ア ショータイム！
We have to watch out for
the one who stopped your kick,
＜「モクハチ」 ２時間スペシャル。
オープニングは華麗なる➡
Shira, and his team, and...
スイング・ジャズから
スタートします。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Survival in the Demon Desert"
演奏は ジェントル・フォレスト・ジャズ・バンドの
皆さんです＞
...the team from the Hidden Waterfall!